Huh?
The bread I bought has been mysteriously
replaced by three 100-yen coins.
Do I take that as
a sign of sincerity?
Tohsaka.
Tohsaka!
You in here?
I wonder what this is.
Sorry.
I'll be... just a
little longer...
Soy
Oyster
Shirou, how are you feeling?
The numbness on
my left side is gone.
It still feels a little
heavy, though.
That is good news.
Good morning, Rin.
Morning.
You seem to have slept
quite soundly last night.
Not really. Somebody kept
making noise well past midnight.
Oh, and we're going out today.
Hurry up and get ready.
Going out? Where?
The next town over.
To do what?
What else? To go
have fun, of course.
It's a date, dummy.
A date?
Between who and who?
Me and you.
Oh, okay.
You and me, huh...
Wh...
Whaaat?
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
Shirou?
What's this about you going
on a date with Tohsaka-san?
The Final Decision
This is your big chance!
Stop messing around.
I don't know what's
going on here, either.
Look at you, getting
all embarrassed!
I'm so jealous! Oh,
to be young again!
You have a date today too,
don't you, Fujimura-sensei?
You do?
Yep, sure do.
But that doesn't mean you two
can get carried away, all right?
See you later!
We should go too.
Indeed.
So, where should we go?
Do you two have any requests?
Don't ask me.
Should've known. And you, Saber?
No. I am merely here
as Shirou's guard.
Please act as though
I am not present.
Really? Then you two are okay with
completely submitting to my every whim?
Don't be so sinister!
Anyway, I said I'd tag along with
you, not go out on a date with you.
I thought it might be nice
for us to take a breather.
Let me stop you there.
All three of us.
That happens to be
what people call a "date."
You won't be very popular if
you don't know when to give in.
With who?
Who, indeed?
Shirou.
Fine, whatever!
I'll tag along with you
wherever you want, then!
Well? Is it good?
Uh... I can't really tell.
What? I'm sure you can
tell it's sweet, at least!
Well, I guess it is way
sweeter than it looks.
Well?
Well what?
They're not bad, I guess.
Yes. They make you
look intellectual, Rin.
Thanks!
Now, which next...
I think these would
look good on you, Saber.
Looking good! And you
try these on, Emiya-kun!
That's hilarious!
I will never, ever
wear glasses, got it?
I look young enough already!
Oh, right.
You're self-conscious
about that.
I don't think you have anything
to worry about, Emiya-kun.
You're perfectly
fine as you are.
No, I'm not!
I have to grow a little taller.
You're pretty average, I'd say.
I'm nowhere near average!
I have to grow at
least as tall as Issei!
Don't worry about it. You'll
grow plenty taller, I'm sure.
Based on what?
Um, you've got a solid build, so
I bet you'll fill out if you eat right.
With plenty of photosynthesis,
you'll grow nice and tall!
I think.
Do I look like I have leaves?
Wait, are you angry?
Not really. I'll take your
advice with a grain of salt.
I can't make you any
promises about your height,
but I'm sure you'll become
a great-looking guy.
You have my guarantee
on that part, Shirou.
Ooh, you're blushing!
I love how everything is
written on your face, Emiya-kun.
Geez, you're evil!
Do you get your kicks from teasing
guys in the same year as you?
Of course!
You have the best reactions!
Let's stop playing with Shirou
and start on the main event!
Before lunch, let's knock
a few out of the park!
Take that!
One more time!
That machine's set to 120 kph...
Shirou, what are you
standing around for?
Yeah, I can't let Tohsaka
steal the spotlight!
Saber?
Wh-What is it, Shirou?
I find it uncomfortable to be
stared at in such a manner.
Talk about hating to lose.
I miscalculated.
I had no idea Saber
would be so competitive.
Yeah, she gets angry if you go easy on her,
and she sulks if you get too far ahead...
Y-You were just as eager to
compete against Rin, Shirou!
When the person in the next cage
is going nuts, you get worked up too.
And seriously, you're way
too good at batting, Tohsaka.
Do you do pushups before
going to bed or something?
Y-Yes, I do.
What's wrong with that?
Uh, nothing.
Good game.
Wow. You put way more
effort into this than I expected.
Of course.
When I ask someone
out, I don't kid around.
Oh, that explains one mystery.
This is what you
used the bread for.
I figured you'd just scarfed the
whole loaf as a midnight snack.
Emiya-kun?
Shut your mouth, and let's eat.
Oh. Right.
Let's eat.
Thank you for the meal, Rin.
Huh? Do you not like
spicy food, Shirou?
No, I'm okay.
The seasoning is intense,
but this is really good!
Oh? I'm glad.
You've got some
ketchup on your face.
Shall I get that for you?
Wh-Why would you say that?
Oops. Maybe I
took the joke too far.
Sorry! I knew exactly the reaction
I'd get, so I couldn't help myself.
Whatever. But just you wait.
I'll be cool as a cucumber
from tomorrow on.
Oh? Does that mean I can start
going after you with everything I have?
What a relief! I was so
sick of taking it easy on you.
Uh, I take that back.
I'll need a little more
time, so if you could
keep it at our current
level, that'd be great.
Really? If you say so.
But when you're ready to
step up your game, let me know.
I'll stop pulling my punches
and knock you on your butt.
You're that sure
you'll win, huh?
Are you sure you're
not the Devil herself?
I mean, you're
always wearing red.
You look like
you're feeling better.
Guess you're back to normal.
I'm glad.
Tohsaka.
What?
Why did you come over yesterday?
Let alone sleep over.
Why?
I felt like it, that's all.
I thought it might be
a nice change of pace.
Well, it was fun to
have lots of people over.
Right?
Yeah. It ended up being nothing
special, but thanks anyway.
D-Don't get the wrong idea!
I-I wasn't concerned about you!
Yeah, you'd be at a disadvantage
if you lost your partner.
So you came to see
how I was doing, right?
Th-That's right! I'm
glad you understand.
Yeah. I appreciate it.
I don't know what you were after, but
you really were concerned, weren't you?
That boy Shirou is going
on dates now, bold as can be.
Oh, and get this, Kiritsugu-san. Do
you remember a girl named Saber-chan?
She says she's the daughter
of someone you knew abroad.
Came all this way to visit you.
Abroad, huh?
We never got the chance
to go on a trip, huh?
We made it.
Did you have fun today?
We only got through
half of what I had planned,
but how did you like it?
Well, I haven't goofed
around like that for a long time.
Look, if you had fun,
just come out and say so.
The least you can do is tell me
straight after I played host all day.
Sorry. I didn't mean to be rude.
Yes, you did.
You're subconsciously
slamming on the brakes.
I don't know what
happened to you,
but if it was that bad, wouldn't your
life be a lot happier if you let it go?
Shirou, look outside.
Is something wrong?
I don't know. It's weird.
What?
What is this place?
I can't get through to Archer.
We're completely sealed in.
These are...
This is only serving to
increase their number.
Precisely.
Fighting within my magic field will
only expend your mana to no avail.
You're pulling out all
the stops for us, I see.
As long as there's water, you have
an endless supply of troops, huh?
We cut them off
at the source, then.
How valiant.
But perhaps you ought to look at this
before you raise your sword at me, Saber.
Fuji-nee!
What do you hope to
accomplish by taking a hostage?
I have no business with you.
My interest lies
with that boy there.
Your magic circuits
are fascinating.
I'd like to take them without
killing you, if possible.
Do you understand?
I'm resorting to these
crude tactics because
I wish to win you
over, not kill you.
If you become my puppet,
I shall refrain from
any further violence.
Listen to you! You're doing all
this behind your Master's back!
Is that jealousy I hear?
I hate to disappoint you, but it is
not perfect omnipotence that I desire,
but rather imperfect,
unique abilities.
So, boy, what is your answer?
Such a difficult child. This
should be an easy decision.
No matter how
skilled your Saber is,
she cannot defeat me with
my limitless reserves of mana.
My power is being fed to
me by all who live in this city.
It is as though I have
thousands of Masters.
Do you understand
what I am saying?
You wouldn't dare!
So you do. Even humans who are
devoid of mana still have souls, yes?
And we are soul eaters
by nature, are we not?
By stealing mana in the
form of life from these Masters,
I can extract as much as I like.
Listen, boy, you have
no chance of winning.
Serve me alongside Saber.
Let Fuji-nee go!
Weren't you listening?
I said to surrender to me.
Like hell I will!
Let Fuji-nee go!
So you have no interest in
working with another Master?
No, just not with you.
I seem to be on your bad side.
That really is a shame.
Had you worked with me,
I would have been willing
to share the Grail with you.
I don't care about that.
I promised myself that I'd
fight to stop people like you.
The Grail is irrelevant!
What's so funny?
Oh, did I strike a nerve?
But you have only yourself to blame,
saying things that you don't mean.
After all, you yourself
are a victim of the Grail.
"The Grail is irrelevant"...
The reason you reject it so
strongly is out of hatred, is it not?
Shirou?
I know all about
you, Emiya Shirou.
You lost everything
in the last war.
You were found by Emiya Kiritsugu as you
lay alone in the flames, waiting to die.
And you were made his
son, magic forced upon you,
solely for the next war.
How you must have suffered.
No way...
Emiya-kun? Is that true?
Yes, the Grail has always
been a hated enemy to you.
It is for that very reason
that you have every right
to claim the Grail as
recompense for ten years ago.
And the Grail is
as good as mine.
It would be child's play
to grant you your wish.
You speak nonsense, Caster!
The Grail will not appear
until but one Servant remains!
No, there is a way to
claim it without fighting.
As a Caster, I can sense
the inner workings of the Grail.
Yes, if you, with your massive
mana output, were to assist me,
I could summon the
Grail here and now.
This is your last chance, boy.
You wish to avoid senseless
fighting, do you not?
Then serve me,
Saber's Master!
Never.
I reject your offer.
Are you mad?
Do you understand
the position you are in?
I won't help a witch who
treats people as food.
Your methods are wrong.
And one more thing...
I wasn't forced to
become a mage.
I chose on my own to follow
in my old man's footsteps.
Witch... You called me a witch?
I see. I have no
use for you, then.
You can die here!
Why, you...
Don't do it, Saber!
I'm begging you.
Stay where you are.
Shirou, but she...
Oh, my. I had thought that
you were utterly irrational,
but you do understand
your situation, don't you?
Coward!
You're going to kill
Shirou in cold blood?
Of course not. I'm merely going to
strip him of his status as a Master.
You will not join me, but
you wish to save this girl.
That tells me that you are prepared
to hand over your Command Spells.
All right. How do I do that?
Shirou, no! She won't stop...
I will take them, of
course. Arm and all.
That is enough, Shirou.
I cannot allow you to continue
to play into Caster's hands.
Same here!
I mean, do you honestly think she's
the sort who'd release a hostage?
Take it. That's all
you want, right?
Shirou!
You don't have to go to
such extremes to help others!
I do!
If giving up my arm
will save Fuji-nee's
life, I'll do it without
a second's thought.
You truly are a foolish child!
You are a nuisance, so die!
No! Stop!
Saber!
Are you surprised?
This is my Noble
Phantasm, Rule Breaker!
It nullifies any and all
magic cast in this world.
The dagger of
betrayal and denial.
The pact has been forged.
I am now your Master.
You are now as I am.
Betray your Master, and
pledge your blade to me!
You... You took a Servant,
despite being one yourself?
Yes, I have made
her my familiar.
Saber now belongs to me.
And now I shall return
your friend, little fool.
Fuji-nee!
Fuji-nee! Are you
okay? Fuji-nee!
Fuji-nee...
You know, I think
I shall let you go.
That show you put on was so
wonderful it almost began to irritate me.
However...
Oh. I guess I should've
seen this coming.
Yes. Playtime is
over, young lady.
Now, Saber.
Strike down Archer's Master.
Never! Who would
obey the likes of you?
No, you will obey, Saber.
As long as I have
these Command Spells,
you cannot defy me
in either body or soul.
You idiot! Why did you do that?
What a pity.
Such a waste. That
boy was so fascinating.
Obey my Command Spell, Saber.
Run...
Run, Shirou!
We have to get Fuji-nee...
Just come on!
Impossible!
Saber's magic resistance is even effective
against the binding of a Command Spell?
But be that as it may,
I won't let you escape!
It's about time!
My apologies.
It took quite some time
to breach that magic field.
From the inside, however...
Archer, take Fujimura-sensei!
Now, while we still can!
Saber...
Place Fujimura-sensei
in that room.
Shirou, are you with me?
We're going to walk, okay?
This was for the best.
At least you're alive.
For now, get some
rest, Emiya-kun.
I see. Saber was taken while
I was busy breaching the field.
That's all you have to say?
Yes. But we should
count our blessings that
we now know what
Caster's Noble Phantasm is.
That Caster... Always
sloppy on the follow-through.
Deep down, she might
actually be a decent woman.
You don't seem very
concerned, Archer.
Weren't you rooting for Saber?
I don't recall ever
giving that impression.
What makes you think that, Rin?
Well... Would you believe me if
I said it was women's intuition?
No.
For one, are you even old
enough to qualify as a woman?
You are lacking in feminine
charms, to begin with,
not to mention
refinement. Furthermore...
and this is the most
damning—your appeal is hard to see.
Well, well. You've finally
found your groove again,
haven't you?
Getting back to
the topic at hand,
here's my first piece of evidence
that you were rooting for Saber:
the first time you met her,
you went easy, didn't you?
No matter how powerful Saber is,
I doubt she could have gotten the
better of you. Not with your defenses.
She caught me unawares.
Like you, I'm vulnerable to
unexpected developments.
Oh, get off my case.
The second piece of evidence:
after the incident with Rider, you
tried to provoke Saber, remember?
That was out of character
for you, no two ways about it.
But when I looked at it from
another angle, it made perfect sense.
You were actually
scolding Saber, weren't you?
I'm right? I knew it!
I don't know if you two knew
each other in a previous life or what,
but it's unusual for you
to be so cold to someone.
Is it? As far as I'm aware,
I treat everyone that way.
That's just how it looks to you.
The way I see it,
you're only awkward when it
comes to things dealing with yourself.
You're much smoother when it comes
to others, which is why no one notices.
So, have you finally remembered?
Do you know which
Heroic Spirit you are?
If you have some
connection to Saber,
you ought to be from an
era that's close to hers, right?
No. Everything is still hazy.
But as you say, I do have
memories of this Saber.
However, she does not seem to know
me, so we could not have been very close.
Oh.
More to the point,
Rin, how is your guest?
Luckily, he wasn't
hit anywhere vital.
But his wounds aren't
healing at all this time.
Their pact has been broken,
so he might have lost the healing
ability he'd been getting from Saber.
No, not him. I meant the other.
Oh, Fujimura-sensei?
Caster seems to have put
her under a sleeping spell,
but she's perfectly healthy.
I've treated her, so she could
sleep a whole week with no problems.
Knowing Fujimura-sensei, she
might jump out of bed any moment.
Perhaps, but that woman's
enchantments are more curses than spells.
The simplest way to break
them is to kill the original caster.
That's true.
Defeating Caster
is our top priority.
I know.
If possible, I'd like to do so before
Saber falls completely under her control.
Understood.
So your pact with that
boy is also over, then.
What?
Don't "what" me.
Emiya Shirou is no
longer a Master, correct?
What's this?
Surely you aren't going to say that you
mean to look after him as a fallen comrade.
Hardly. I'm not that soft.
What, then?
It isn't over yet.
Our agreement will stand until he
himself says that he wants out of the war.
I can reject him all I want,
but nothing is over
until he says it is.
Rin...
That's our course of action.
Do you object, Archer?
Would it matter if I did?
I know painfully well that you
won't stop until you have your way.
Let's go, Archer!
Huh?
Where am I?
Nobody's... here?
Which means that she's
out there... by herself...
Sorry... I made a
mess... Tohsaka.
This...
looks familiar...
Oh, right. It's the same
as the one from that night.
Don't do this to me...
Why did it have to be you?
Why did you have to pick this
hour, on this day, to be here?
No. There's still a way.
Damn it... What the hell?
She's always going on
about debts and favors,
but this is one debt
I can never repay!
Tohsaka...
Are you listening, Assassin?
I believe I instructed you to
continue guarding the front gate.
There was an intruder, you see.
I spotted an unusual
bird, so I struck it down.
Is this something
used by your kind?
Yes. It is a familiar
used for espionage.
That young lady
has terrible luck.
If she were slightly less talented, I
would have taken her on as my pupil.
I leave my Master's
defense to you, Assassin.
Guard the gate
with your very life.
Ever since I've been summoned,
I, Kojirou, have never truly felt alive.
Ordering such a person to do
or die is meaningless, is it not?
Don't quibble.
You are a Servant
that I summoned.
If you cannot pledge fealty to your lord,
I shall simply eliminate you right now.
I see. Goodness me.
My life is as insubstantial
as a shimmering heat haze,
but I would rather it not
be extinguished just yet.
After all, I do have
a promise to keep.
Then hold your tongue.
Your only concern
is guarding this place.
Then guard it I shall.
But is this wise, Caster?
I am also disloyal to my lord, but you are
acting on your own authority far too often.
Your errand tonight is also without
your Master's knowledge, I'd wager.
Day by day, you overstep your
bounds ever further, Caster...
Silence. The next time
you make me repeat myself,
I'll eliminate you without
waiting out the next five days.
Oh, dear. They say that women
and children are difficult to deal with.
It would appear
that is indeed true.
Worry not. I understand.
This is all to be carried out without
your Master's knowledge, yes?
Yours is a touching tale.
I only hope that your love
for your lord should reach him.
Assassin, mind your...
I am a sore loser.
Allow me these witless jests.
On my blade,
I swear I shall protect this gate
from all, no matter who they be.
But where might you be going?
Do you not trust my protection?
Of course not. You are
merely my insurance.
But I no longer
require that, either.
With Saber now mine, I no longer need
to make this rustic place my sanctuary.
A change of location?
Meaning that you have
no further use for me.
There is a sacred spot
superior to this mountain?
Yes. A place which
suits me perfectly.
I will be leaving to claim
my prize ahead of schedule.
I now have a new
fortification, the Grail,
and even a new pawn
in the form of Saber.
With all these, even my
reticent Master will be unable
to offer up any objections
to my plan of action.
Once I have the Grail, I
will have nothing to fear.
Yes, for then none will be able to stand
against me, no matter who they may be!
Caster.
Have we met before, my
good overseer of this mad ritual?
What do you want, Caster?
This place is inviolable
neutral territory.
No Servant may enter this place, regardless
of which Heroic Spirit they may be.
The rules have changed.
Command Spells?
Saber...
Saber is now my puppet.
You understand what
that means, I take it?
The outcome of this war
is as good as decided.
Is there something wrong with
coming to claim my prize early?
Indeed there is.
The Grail will not appear
until but one Servant remains.
As a Servant, surely you were made aware
of this at the time of your summoning.
Yes, the Grail did say that.
It ordered me to go
forth and slay the other
Heroic Spirits in
order to activate it.
However,
that refers to the
Greater Grail, does it not?
Tell me, where is
the Lesser Grail?
You priests are in charge of
the Grail's key, are you not?
There is no Holy Grail here.
Do you wish to die?
Don't make idle threats.
You betray yourself,
Princess of Colchis.
You still have no stomach
for brutality, do you?
You just want me to
stand by and watch, right?
No one's going to interfere.
This era has fine
warriors too, I see.
But how long will his
fighting spirit last, I wonder?
Tohsaka... Where are you?
Why are you here?
Go home.
I don't know what you're trying to
prove, but you're being a nuisance.
I'm not going anywhere.
I promised that I'd fight
alongside you, remember?
Forget about that
stupid promise.
I mean, what can you
possibly do as you are now?
You've lost Saber.
I...
Besides, there's no
need for you to fight now.
You're not a Master anymore.
Take shelter in the
church, and you'll be safe.
Don't be stupid! I can't
leave Saber like that!
So no matter what, I'm
gonna fight to the bitter en...
Look at yourself.
You've had Saber to help you until
now, but you're a wreck without her.
Besides, for all your
talk about Saber,
what happens to her is
no longer your concern.
You're wrong. I may
not be a Master anymore,
but I could tell
she was in anguish.
I won't leave her
in Caster's grasp!
I see.
The problem is,
you're powerless.
If you refuse to admit
it, I'll tell you straight:
there's nothing you can do
to help Saber as you are now.
That's all there is to say.
You've lost Saber, and
you're no longer a Master.
There's no longer any reason for you
to remain involved in the Holy Grail War,
so bow out here.
Hold up, Tohsaka!
That may be true, but...
- Your dream for the
future - yume ni miteita
What are you
thinking, you idiot?
Seems unattainable
ano hi no kage ni
even through all your toil
todokanai sakebi
No matter what you do,
asu no jibun wa
you cannot give up
nante egaite mo
on hoping for brighter days
kienai negai ni nureru
In your hand you hold
koboreochiru kakera wo
the fragments of our lives
tsukamu sono te de
Stay your heart of doubt
yureru kokoro kakaete
and soar through the night
tobikonda ike yoru he
Relying on others
dareka wo ate ni shitemo
will not help you
find your true self
motomeru mono ja nai no dakara
Dispel this illusion
hontou no jibun
wa koko ni iru tte
and open your eyes
me wo tojite inaide
Stay out of this from here on,
or you're dead.
The wind spreads
long-forgotten smiles
like dusty old paper
Praying for the power
to accomplish more tomorrow
is only making it harder for you
Your body has grown hard as ice
even as your dream is budding
Fly towards the dawn
before you turn to ash
Relying on others
will not help you
find your true self
Dispel this illusion
and open your eyes
Isn't it enough to
live for the moment
and dedicate it to others
Abandon your pretense
and be yourself
Will you be able to believe you made
the right choices until the very end?
No, I comprehend the situation.
Has the matter
outside been resolved?
Shirou, get back!
You've been protecting me of
your own free will, haven't you?
Shall we reenact a
battle of legend here?
Archer...
You're... You can't be!
Broadcast Starts April 2015